Paul Edgecomb didn't believe in miracles. Until the day he met one.
The Green Mile is a fantasy, drama, crime film directed by Frank Darabont.
A supernatural tale set on death row in a Southern prison, where gentle giant John
Coffey possesses the mysterious power to heal people's ailments.
When the cell block's head guard, Paul Edgecomb, recognizes Coffey's miraculous gift,
he tries desperately to help stave off the condemned man's execution.
Paul Edgecomb, played by Tom Hanks.
Brutus 'Brutal' Howell, played by David Morse.
Jan Edgecomb, played by Bonnie Hunt.
John Coffey, played by Michael Clarke Duncan.
Warden Hal Moores, played by James Cromwell.
Eduard Delacroix, played by Michael Jeter.
The Green Mile is a 1999 American fantasy drama film written and directed by
Frank Darabont and based on the 1996 novel by Stephen King.
It stars Tom Hanks as a death row prison guard during the Great Depression who witnesses supernatural
events following the arrival of an enigmatic convict (Michael Clarke Duncan) at his facility.
The Green Mile was released by Warner Bros.
in the United States on December 10, 1999, to positive reviews from critics, who praised Darabont's direction and writing,
emotional weight, and performances (particularly for Hanks and Duncan), although its length received some criticism.
It was a commercial success, grossing $286.8 million from its $60 million budget, and was nominated for four
Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Supporting Actor for Duncan, Best Sound, and Best Adapted Screenplay.
The film explores themes of mentally disabled, death penalty,
based on novel or book, southern usa, psychopath.
The tone is emotional.